It'll send a chill down your spine.
Ghostbusters: Frozen Empire is a fantasy, adventure,
comedy film directed by Gil Kenan.
When the discovery of an ancient artifact unleashes an evil force, Ghostbusters new and old
must join forces to protect their home and save the world from a second Ice Age.
Phoebe Spengler, played by Mckenna Grace.
Gary Grooberson, played by Paul Rudd.
Callie Spengler, played by Carrie Coon.
Trevor Spengler, played by Finn Wolfhard.
Ray Stantz, played by Dan Aykroyd.
Nadeem, played by Kumail Nanjiani.
Ghostbusters: Frozen Empire is a 2024 American supernatural comedy film
directed by Gil Kenan, and written by Kenan and Jason Reitman.
It is the fifth in the Ghostbusters film series.
The film features Paul Rudd, Carrie Coon, Finn Wolfhard and Mckenna Grace reprising their roles from the previous film, with Ernie Hudson
and Annie Potts reprising their characters from the earlier films, and Kumail Nanjiani and Patton Oswalt joining the cast.
It sees the veteran Ghostbusters returning to New York City and collaborating
with their successors to save the world from a new ancient evil.
Following the success of Ghostbusters: Afterlife, Sony Pictures announced
the sequel in April 2022, with Reitman returning as director.
In December, co-writer and executive producer Kenan took over as
director, with Reitman remaining as co-writer and co-producer.
The same month, Rudd, Coon, Wolfhard, Grace, Hudson, Potts, Bill Murray and
Dan Aykroyd were all confirmed to be reprising their roles.
New cast members including Nanjiani and Oswalt were announced in March 2023, with
principal photography commencing that month and wrapping in June.
Dario Marianelli composed the film's score.
As the first film in the Ghostbusters franchise to be released following the death of the franchise's co-creator and Jason
Reitman's father Ivan Reitman, who posthumously receives credit as a producer, the film is dedicated to his memory.
Ghostbusters: Frozen Empire had its premiere at the AMC Lincoln Square Theater in New York City on March
14, 2024, and was released in the United States on March 22 by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed
$202 million on a budget of $100 million.
The film explores themes of new york city,
supernatural, ghostbuster, sequel, teenage girl.
The tone is lighthearted.